novascotia.com 2013-10-17

# Privacy Policy

Some information contained within the website has been obtained by outside sources. Although every effort has been made to ensure accuracy, currency and reliability of content, the Nova Scotia Department of Economic and Rural Development and Tourism accepts no responsibility for any errors or omissions, whether caused by data entry, programming error, computer malfunction or any other possible circumstance that may result in misinformation or malfunction. 

Any links to other websites are suggested as sources of more information about tourism in Nova Scotia. The Nova Scotia Department of Economic and Rural Development and Tourism is not an agent for, and does not recommend or endorse for any purpose, any person, or product referred to in any of these linked websites. 

Government of Nova Scotia websites are covered by the [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](http://nslegislature.ca/legc/statutes/freedom.htm). Our privacy policy arises from that Act, other legislation, and fair information practices. 

On our websites, we collect personal information about you only when you explicitly provide it. Examples of that collection would be when you renew your vehicle registration, apply for a marriage certificate online, or request tourist information to be mailed to you. We protect the personal information given to us when you fill out a form. We have implemented a variety of security measures to ensure that your personal information is not lost, misused, altered, or unintentionally destroyed. 

By "personal information" we mean any information about you as an identifiable individual including your name, an identifying number such as your driver's licence number, your birth date, your email address, or your credit card information. (For other examples, see: [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](http://nslegislature.ca/legc/statutes/freedom.htm), section 3(1) (i)) 

We do not provide personal information gathered on the websites to third parties except with your express permission or as permitted by law. (For example, see: [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](http://nslegislature.ca/legc/statutes/freedom.htm), section 27) 

We may release or use your personal information provided on the websites for the purpose for which it was provided or for a compatible purpose. We may also do so if we are permitted under law, such as under a subpoena, or to collect a debt owing to the province. This may include sharing information within the government when it is necessary. (For example, see: [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](http://nslegislature.ca/legc/statutes/freedom.htm), sections 26 & 27) 

You are entitled to correct any personal information gathered through the websites that we hold about you. If you want to correct your personal information, there will be an appropriate contact listed for you to direct enquiries. If no contact is identified, then you should contact the webmaster of the relevant site. (For example, see: [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](http://nslegislature.ca/legc/statutes/freedom.htm), section 25) 

Government websites may use cookies or tracking devices during your visit to our website. Information gathered by these technologies will disappear once you leave the website, with the following exceptions: feedback forms such as quick polls, contests, and surveys. A persistent cookie is set to help prevent duplicate entries or multiple submissions. This cookie is not linked to any personally identifiable information. 

Government web servers automatically collect some information about a visitor's computer or other access device, such as its Internet protocol address or browser version, in their logs. This information is used in aggregate form for statistical purposes only. 

novascotia.com uses a variety of Google Applications, including Google Analytics, Google Earth and Google Maps, to provide users with relevant information and to enhance their online experience. Through these applications, Google collects users’ IP addresses. You are offered choices when asked for personal information, such as the ability to decline providing the information and/or refuse cookies in your browser. However, this may prevent personalized services from being provided and you may not be able to take full advantage of all the features available. 

To learn more about how Google collects and stores IP address, please see [Google's Privacy Centre](http://www.google.com/privacy.html). Further information on Google Applications and Google’s policies on the protection of personal information, can be found through [Google's Privacy FAQ](http://www.google.com/privacy_faq.html).

Nova Scotia Tourism Agency
